Soyoung Kim

LinkedIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/koyoungk/

Profile

A detail-oriented and knowledge-driven English-Korean localisation specialist with experience in translation, functionality and LQA testing, translation management, and social media management. Works with enthusiasm taking pride in delivered products, specialised in the video game and blockchain industry, yet experienced in a range of other areas from simultaneous translation during telephone/video conferences, academic papers, legal documents, websites, IT softwares, sports and social network posts. At Rockstar Games LQA studio, contributed to Asian UI Font Design for Red Dead Redemption 2, with extensive research on Korean font styles that are similar to the original ones, coordinating Asian UI Font testing group, suggesting the appropriate font size across all areas of the game, creating the Localisation UI - Font wiki/confluence page for educational purposes, working closely with the devs. Experience in managing a small translation team of 7, involved in recruiting, training, workflow management, handling multi-language files, reviewing and invoicing. Also worked as an English Content Creator & Social Media Manager for a blockchain project.

Skills

As a Korean native having lived abroad for 10 years, I am fluent in both written and spoken English. B2 in Spanish (current residence) and conversational Japanese. In general tech-savvy with experience in productivity softwares such as Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Creative Suite, MemoQ, Smartling, MemSource, Github, Notepad++ and i18n Editor and other project management/communication tools such as Trello, Asana, Discord, Slack, Jira, Confluence etc. Used to manage English content on various platforms such as Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Reddit, Youtube, Medium, Steemit and MailChimp (Newsletter).

Professional Experience

FREELANCE KOREAN TRANSLATOR & LQA TESTER

List of Current LQA Client

- **MoGi Group**, Dublin, Ireland (Sep 2019 Present)
- **Allcorrect Group**, *Dublin, Ireland (Sep 2018 Present)*

List of Current Translation (&LQA) Client

- **Beluga Linguistics**, *Madrid*, *Spain (April 2021 Present)*
- **Samba Digital**, *Miami*, *US* (May 2021 Present)
- **Testronic**, Warsaw, Poland (February 2021 Present)
- **Terra Translations**, Wisconsin, USA (March 2019 Present)
- **EC Innovations**, Chicago, Illinois, USA (March 2019 Present)
- Lilt Inc, San Fransisco, USA (December 2019 Present)
- **Byword**, London, UK (November 2019 Present)
- **Universally Speaking**, Bedford, UK (December 2018 Present)
- WORBLI Foundations, *Valley Point, Singapore (December 2018 October 2019)*

CONTENT CREATOR & SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGEMENT, eosDAC, United Kingdom (May 2018 – October 2019)

- Started out as a **Korean Community Manager**, provided analyses on social media trend in the Korean blockchain market, translations of the website, the software, promotional materials and Whitepaper, interview video subtitling, and simultaneous translation between devs and investors
- Promoted to **Translation Manager** of 7 languages, involved in recruiting, training, workflow management and reviewing
- Moved to English Social Media & Content Creation Manager, planning content, writing blog articles and managing social media accounts

KOREAN LOCALISATION TESTER, Rockstar Games, Lincoln, United Kingdom (May 2015 – May 2018)

- Translating, proofreading, editing in-game texts, legal texts, marketing materials and website texts
- Testing and reporting both linguistic and functionality bugs in-game and on the website
- Handling HTML files and Compliance terminology issues, legally uncleared trademarks
- Acting Korean Senior and Associate Task Team Leader to coordinate the Korean team and the all-language task team when the lead was absent
- Giving presentations to new starts as a member of the Sports and Social Committee
- Organising corporate events as part of Sports and Social Committee
- Voluntarily involved in creating In-house portal Wiki pages for more efficient workflow

TRANSLATOR & REVIEWER, Kakyo Translation and Notary Service, Seoul, South Korea (January 2014 – April 2014)

Worked for a certified translation and visa (immigration) aid company, carrying out:

• Translating and proofreading documents ranging from company financial statements to papers required for studying/immigrant visa application on both sides from Korean to English

Project

- OlliOlli World | Roll7, Private Division | Video Game
- Spelunky 1 | Derek Yu, Mossmouth, Blitworks | Video Game
- The last Campfire | Hello Games | Video Game
- CrossFireX | Remedy Entertainment, Smilegate, Xbox Game Studios | Video Game
- Shooty Skies | Mighty Games, Hipster Whale | Video Game
- **Cubism** | Thomas Van Bouwel, Vanbo LLC | Video Game
- Beat Saber | Beat Games | Video Game
- Tangle Tower | SFB Games | Video Game
- **CONTROL** | Remedy Games | Video Game
- eosDAC Member Client and eosdac.io | eosDAC | Blockchain Software and website
- Red Dead Redemption 2 | Rockstar Games | Video Game
- Grand Theft Auto Online | Rockstar Games | Video Game
- Social Club | Rockstar Games | Website

Education

BACHELOR'S IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, Ajou University, Suwon, South Korea, 2014